[Music]
observational studies like these
suggesting dairy might not be so bad can
be confounded by extraneous factors such
as the fact that people who eat more
cheese tend to be of higher
socioeconomic class
fine
bored about this
interventional study a randomized
crossover trial which compared a
high-fat cheese diet to a high-fat meat
diet to a low-fat diet a high cheese
diet cheese which is loaded with
saturated fat a high meat diet meat
which is loaded with saturated fat
versus carb a low fat diet and people
ended up with the same
cholesterol
levels let's see
how they did it
half the study was paid for in part by
the dairy industry and the other half
paid for by dairy dairy dairy and dairy
if you're the dairy industry and you're
trying to design a study to show that a
high cheese diet doesn't raise
cholesterol how would you go about doing
that
anyone remember this video it's one of
my favorites the beef industry was in
the same pickle as the cheese industry
beef has saturated fat which raises
cholesterol which raises the risk of
dying from our number one killer what's
an industry to do
so they designed a study where they
added beef
and cholesterols went down
how is that possible here's the two
diets they added beef and the
cholesterol went down they did this by
cutting out so much dairy pork poultry
fish and eggs that their overall
saturated fat intake was cut in half
they cut saturated fat levels in half
and the cholesterol levels went down
well duh
they could have swapped in twinkies and
said snack cakes lower your cholesterol
or frosting or anything okay so now that
you know the trick
let's go back to this study
how are you going to get a high-fat
cheese diet and a high-fat meat diet to
have anywhere near the same saturated
fat level as a diet with neither
unless
wait
don't tell me what they added coconut
oil or something to the other diet
they added so much coconut oil and
cookies to the so-called low-fat diet
that they were able to sufficiently
raise the level of saturated fat to
cause a similar rise in cholesterol
that's how you can make a cheese or
meat-rich diet look like it doesn't
raise cholesterol
that reminds me of the desperation
evident in this study that compared the
effects of dairy cheddar cheese to a
non-dairy cheddar cheese called daia
milk consumption has plummeted in recent
years as people have discovered
plant-based alternatives like soy milk
and almond milk and now there's
plant-based cheese alternatives what's
the national dairy council to do
how are you going to design a study
that shows it's healthier to eat cheese
designer study where cheese causes less
inflammation than the vegan alternative
they got their work cut out for them
they had no health food by any stretch
but definitely
three times less saturated fat than
couches
so
i give up how could you possibly show
more inflammation from daia
well there is one fat that may cause
more inflammation than milk fat palm oil
in fact may raise cholesterol levels as
much as trans fat laden partially
hydrogenated oil
yeah but what are you telling me they
like slipped the day of group some extra
palm oil on the side
yes can you believe it they compared
cheese
today a plus palm oil
so much extra palm oil that the vegan
alternative meal ended up having the
same amount of saturated fat as the
cheese meal that's like
proving tofu is worse than beef by doing
a study where they compared a beef
burger to a tofu patty stuffed with lard
oh wait the meat industry already did
that
but at least they had the decency to
concede that replacement of meat by tofu
in the habitual diet would probably not
usually be accompanied by the addition
of lard
[Music]
uh